Guide to the John D. Mattox Papers
John D. Mattox Papers
1860-1998
1860 1998
Mattox John D.
MC 00261
The John D. Mattox Papers contain photographic prints, negatives, and contact sheets, and papers depicting the personal and professional life of John D. Mattox. Personal portraits and snapshots document the lives of Mattox, his wife Mary, their son Douglas, and their extended family. Also included are photographs of the town of Wendell, North Carolina, where the Mattox family lived. The collection also includes photographs taken while Mattox served in Europe during World War II. Relating to Mattox’s professional career as a photographer at North Carolina State University, there are many images of campus scenes, student and faculty portraits, and campus publications featuring Mattox’s work. Wedding photographs, miscellaneous portraits, unidentified original and copied tintypes and cartes de visite, as well as rolled 35 mm negatives are also included. While the majority of the collection is composed of photographs, there are some papers such as news clippings, correspondence, business cards, awards, brochures, and grade reports which belonged to Mattox.
John Douglas Mattox, Sr. (1911-1987) was a photographer with the Visual Aids Department at North Carolina State University from 1949 to 1974. A native of Wendell, North Carolina, Mattox attended North Carolina State College (later North Carolina State University) in the 1930s and enlisted in the Army in 1941, serving in Europe. He married the former Mary Elizabeth Davis of Columbia, South Carolina, and had a son John Douglas Mattox, Jr., called Doug. Mattox was a talented amateur musician and director of the North Carolina State University R.O.T.C. Glee Club.
6 linear feet
North Carolina State University Libraries, Special Collections Research Center
Donated by John Douglas Mattox, Jr., December, 1998.
Gift of Doug Mattox, 1998 (Accession no. 1998-0013).
The collection is arranged into the following series: Personal Photographs; Extended Family Photographs; Wendell, NC, Photographs; World War II Photographs; North Carolina State University Photographs; Wedding Photographs; Miscellaneous Photographs; Unidentified Photographs; Rolled Negatives; and Papers. Within the series, photographs are arranged and labeled as received.
John Douglas Mattox, Sr. (1911-1987) was a photographer with the Visual Aids Department at North Carolina State University from 1949 to 1974. A native of Wendell, North Carolina, Mattox attended North Carolina State College (later North Carolina State University) in the 1930s and enlisted in the Army in 1941, serving in Europe. He married the former Mary Elizabeth Davis of Columbia, South Carolina, and had a son John Douglas Mattox, Jr., called Doug. Mattox was a talented amateur musician and director of the North Carolina State University R.O.T.C. Glee Club.
The John D. Mattox Papers contain photographic prints, negatives, and contact sheets, and papers depicting the personal and professional life of John D. Mattox. Personal portraits and snapshots document the lives of Mattox, his wife Mary, their son Douglas, and their extended family. Also included are photographs of the town of Wendell, North Carolina, where the Mattox family lived. The collection also includes photographs taken while Mattox served in Europe during World War II. Relating to Mattox’s professional career as a photographer at North Carolina State University, there are many images of campus scenes, student and faculty portraits, and campus publications featuring Mattox’s work. Wedding photographs, miscellaneous portraits, unidentified original and copied tintypes and cartes de visite, as well as rolled 35 mm negatives are also included. While the majority of the collection is composed of photographs, there are some papers such as news clippings, correspondence, business cards, awards, brochures, and grade reports which belonged to Mattox.
Mattox Doug; Mattox John D.; North Carolina State University--Students--Photographs; North Carolina State University--Buildings--Photographs; North Carolina State University--History--20th century; North Carolina State University--Students--Social life and customs; North Carolina State University--Faculty--Photographs; North Carolina State University--Photographs; Mattox Mary; North Carolina State University--Alumni and alumnae; North Carolina State University Reserve Officer Training Corps--Photographs; Photographs World War, 1939-1945; Black-and-white photographs; Bands (Music); North Carolina Churches; Glee club; Portrait photographs; Wendell (N.C.); Raleigh (N.C.); France; Belgium; Germany; Netherlands; Glass negatives; Postcards; Veterans World War, 1939-1945; Agriculture; Carte de visite photographs; Clippings; Tintype; England; Weddings.; Slides (Photography); Negatives Photography; War and society
- Personal Photographs
  This series contains portraits and snapshots of John Mattox, his wife Mary, and their son Douglas. The earliest photographs, depicting John Mattox’s early life, are from the 1910s and 1920s. However, the majority of photographs are from the 1940s to the 1970s. These photographs document the Mattox family’s home life including birthday parties, holidays, anniversaries, and social events.
  - Johnny & Edward at Table with Mary and Douglas (neg), Jan 27, 1964 (Box 1)
  - John & Mary Mattox dressed for Annie Sue's Wedding (neg) (Box 1)
  - John & Mary Mattox with family (neg), circa 1940s (Box 1)
  - Snow, Douglas, Bill, & Mary (neg), Dec 11, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Doug's Car - VW (neg), 1967 (Box 1)
  - Mary's Bridge Club, Mattox home, Wall St. (Neg), March 24, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Douglas Birthday (neg), 1958 (Box 1)
  - Mary and Douglas in Wyatt Earp Suit (neg), May 1957 (Box 1)
  - Christmas Party, Egg Nog (neg), Jan 4, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Douglas on Yard Swing (neg) (Box 1)
  - Douglas and Children at Christmas Tree at Home (neg), 1960 (Box 1)
  - Douglas Mattox Standing at Table (Neg), Sept 1, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Annie Sue and Mary at Table (Neg), Christmas 1956 (Box 1)
  - Douglas with Erector Set (Neg), Dec 29, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Douglas Portrait About Age 5 (Neg) (Box 1)
  - Douglas Mattox Portrait (Neg), Jan 11, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Douglas Mattox Portrait (Print), Jan 11, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Douglas Birthday Party (neg), Sept 14, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Christmas Tree - First Year Artificial Tree Used (neg), Dec 24, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Christmas Tree - First Year Artificial Tree Used (Print), Dec 24, 1972 (Box 1)
  - J.D. Mattox - Living Room (neg), about 1967 (Box 1)
  - Douglas Portrait - made in store downtown (neg) (Box 1)
  - Mary & Douglas with Mary's Birthday Cake (neg), Feb 13, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Douglas Mattox Fifth Birthday (neg), Sept 14, 1953 (Box 1)
  - Mary and Douglas in Front Yard, Easter Sunday (neg), 1956 (Box 1)
  - Douglas and Christmas Tree (neg), Dec 25, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Douglas Birthday Party at Women's Club (neg), Sept. 1959 (Box 1)
  - Douglas - Christmas Wind Up Train (neg) (Box 1)
  - Douglas and Boots (dog) on the sofa (neg), April 2, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Douglas and Boys Playing Marbles (neg), May 1958 (Box 1)
  - Mary & Douglas at C.V. Print Exhibit by Visual Aids (neg), Feb 13, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Douglas in Tuxedo - School Dance (neg), June 1966 (Box 1)
  - Mary at Blackboard, Whitley H. School, Wendell, N.C. (print), 1965 - 1966 (Box 1)
  - Mary at Blackboard, Whitley H. School, Wendell, N.C. (neg), 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - Douglas in Cub Scout Suit (neg), 1958 (Box 1)
  - Mary & John with Douglas and Boots (dog) at Christmas Tree (neg), Dec 27, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Douglas - 7th Grade Christmas Dinner and Program, Miss Nancy Spry teacher (Print), Dec 21, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Douglas - 7th Grade Christmas Dinner and Program, Miss Nancy Spry teacher (neg), Dec 21, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Douglas on Tractor Flat Stock Show Wendell, N.C. (neg), Sept 25, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Douglas - Third Grade Class, Mrs. Todd teacher (neg), Oct 1956 (Box 1)
  - Douglas - Third Grade Class, Mrs. Todd teacher (Print), Oct 1956 (Box 1)
  - Douglas & Marion Bain, Douglas in Rabbit Suit (neg), Mar 7, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Mary - School Portraits (neg), Dec 1979 (Box 1)
  - Douglas - Baby Pictures (neg) (Box 1)
  - Douglas Birthday (neg), 1957 (Box 1)
  - Christmas Party(?) (Print), circa 1970s (Box 1)
  - Mary Mattox (44 years old) (Print), Dec 1963 (Box 1)
  - Mary Mattox (44 years old) (neg), Dec 1963 (Box 1)
  - Announcement Picture (John, Mary, Family) (neg) (Box 1)
  - Douglas - Baby Pictures (neg) (Box 1)
  - Douglas Portrait (Print), 1951 (Box 1)
  - Douglas Portrait (neg), 1951 (Box 1)
  - Douglas, Mary, & John Mattox Portrait (Print), Nov 1961 (Box 1)
  - Douglas, Mary, & John Mattox Portrait (neg), Nov 1961 (Box 1)
  - Mary Mattox Portrait (Print), circa 1940s (Box 1)
  - Douglas playing on floor and dog with kitten on back (neg), 1958 (Box 1)
  - John, Mary, & Douglas Mattox (Prints), Dec 9, 1956 (Box 1)
  - John, Mary, & Douglas Mattox (neg), Dec 9, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Douglas - Camera - Roll Film (neg) (Box 1)
  - John & Doug Mattox outside (neg) (Box 1)
  - Mary Mattox Baby Shower, Douglas as a Newborn (neg) (Box 1)
  - Douglas Mattox Portraits (Print) (Box 1)
  - Mary Mattox Portraits (Print) (Box 1)
  - Mary & Douglas Mattox Portraits (Print), Jan 30, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Douglas Mattox in Sargent Uniform (neg), Jan 3, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Douglas Mattox in Sargent Uniform (Print), Jan 3, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Douglas and his 3rd Grade Class on Stage (neg), May 1957 (Box 1)
  - Douglas & 2nd Grade class play at Wendell School (neg), March 7, 1956 (Box 1)
  - 4th grade at Pullen Park, Mrs. Todd - teacher (neg), May 22, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Mary Mattox portrait, school picture (neg), Oct 1971 (Box 1)
  - Mary Mattox portrait, school picture (Print), Oct 1971 (Box 1)
  - Mary Mattox portraits in Living Room (neg), May 1, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Mary Mattox portraits in Living Room (Print), May 1, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Mrs. John Mattox - Wedding (neg), Feb 1, 1943 (Box 1)
  - Family Photos - Mary Davis (neg), June 2, 1942 (Box 1)
  - Douglas & Warrior Club (neg), May 27, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Mary & Douglas Mattox in Front Yard (neg), Aug 7, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Douglas Mattox Portrait (neg), Aug 14, 1953 (Box 1)
  - Mary & Family copies (neg) (Box 1)
  - Mary & Family, Easter at Annie Sue's (neg), 1957 (Box 1)
  - Douglas Birthday (neg), 1952 (Box 1)
  - Douglas and girl, Mascots for Senior Class (neg), June 1953 (Box 1)
  - Douglas and girl, Mascots for Senior Class (Print), June 1953 (Box 1)
  - Mary Mattox portraits (neg), March 25, 1967 (Box 1)
  - John & Mary Mattox, 25th Wedding Anniversary (neg), Feb 1, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Mary Mattox at Christmas Party (neg), Jan 1970 (Box 1)
  - Douglas Mattox with Snowman (neg), Feb 2, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Mary & John Mattox in Indiana (neg) (Box 1)
  - Douglas & Children at Annie Sues & Mossie in group (neg), Oct 1956 (Box 1)
  - Douglas Mattox in Bathtub (neg), May 1956 (Box 1)
  - Family Pictures, Atlanta (neg), 1943 (Box 1)
  - Family Pictures, Atlanta (neg), 1943 (Box 1)
  - Douglas Entering school (neg), Sept 2, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Douglas Mattox, Graduation mascot in cap & gown (neg) (Box 1)
  - Douglas Mattox (neg), Sept 23, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Mattox home, before oil tank (neg), Sept 1953 (Box 1)
  - Douglas, Christmas (neg), 1953 (Box 1)
  - Douglas, age 5 (neg), Jan 23, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Kids at Easter in S.C. (neg) (Box 1)
  - Douglas 5th birthday (neg), Sept 14, 1953 (Box 1)
  - Douglas Mattox at Aunt Martha's (neg) (Box 1)
  - Mary & Douglas at Manteo (neg), Aug 19,1958 (Box 1)
  - Douglas Mattox Birthday Party (neg), Sept 14, 1951 (Box 1)
  - Snow - Wendell, N.C. (neg), Feb 1966 (Box 1)
  - Mary's Roll Film (neg), Sept 1955 (Box 1)
  - Mary & Mrs. Davis Portrait Copies (neg) (Box 1)
  - Truck Parked in Driveway (neg), 1964 (Box 1)
  - Truck Parked in Driveway (Print), 1964 (Box 1)
  - Termite Treatment, John Mattox home - Rhodes Exterminators (neg), April 1, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Christmas Tree Cut from Yard (neg), Dec 25, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Douglas in Tuxedo, High school prom (neg), 1965 (Box 1)
  - Douglas at Dance Party at Women's Club (neg) (Box 1)
  - Douglas (4 years, 10 months) and Mary (neg), July 1953 (Box 1)
  - Douglas sitting on table in front of window (neg), Dec 11, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Snow Scenes at Mattox home (neg), Feb 1965 (Box 1)
  - Douglas & boys playing in front yard (neg), 1956 (Box 1)
  - Mary Mattox, school portraits (neg), May 1980 (Box 1)
  - Mary Mattox, school portraits (Print), May 1980 (Box 1)
  - Mary Mattox in Atlanta (neg) (Box 1)
  - Marion Bain & Douglas in Chair (neg), Sept 27, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Rear of House before Heating Plant was Installed (neg) (Box 1)
  - Douglas and children in Halloween costumes (Print), Oct 19, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Douglas and children in Halloween costumes (neg), Oct 19, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Mary & John Mattox at Dance (neg) (Box 1)
  - Mary & John Mattox at Dance (Print) (Box 1)
  - Christmas 1961 (neg), Jan 5, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Christmas Tree & New Car (neg), 1967 (Box 1)
  - Douglas and New Tractor at Christmas Tree (neg), 1951 (Box 1)
  - Mary Mattox in Charleston costume - PTA show at Wendell School Auditorium (neg), Nov 10, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Douglas, science project (neg), 1964 (Box 1)
  - Douglas and boys playing football in front yard (neg) (Box 1)
  - Douglas Mattox (age 9) with train at Christmas tree (neg), Dec 1957 (Box 1)
  - Douglas birthday dinner (neg), Sept 14, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Mary, Eddy, & Family at Christmas tree at Mama's (neg) (Box 1)
  - Douglas Mattox in bed with books and in backyard with tractor (neg), April 19, 1952 (Box 1)
  - New Room Construction (neg), Feb 29, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Douglas & Conley boys fishing (neg), Nov 17, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Douglas & Conley boys fishing (Print), Nov 17, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Mary & Douglas at Christmas tree (neg), 1959 (Box 1)
  - East side of house at Wall St. (neg), Aug 7, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Mattox group at Thanksgiving Dinner (neg), Nov 1968 (Box 1)
  - Family Christmas Dinner (neg) (Box 1)
  - Douglas Mattox (6 years) Portrait (neg), March 5, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Mary Mattox and Others at Christmas Party (Print) (Box 1)
  - Douglas Mattox - Cowboy Suit (neg), March 4, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Douglas Mattox - 1st Science Exhibit (neg), March 10, 1963 (Box 1)
  - John, Mary, & Douglas Mattox in Yard (neg), Oct 1, 1955 (Box 1)
  - John, Mary, & Douglas Mattox in Yard (Print), Oct 1, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Mamma, Mary & John, Ricey. Film exposed about 1946 in Atlanta (neg), July 3, 1951 (Box 1)
  - House - Interiors (before) (neg), Oct 21, 1953 (Box 1)
  - Personal - Mary, Car, House, etc. (neg), 1974 (Box 1)
  - Mattox House before Repair and Underpinning (neg), April 8, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Mattox Misc. - Mary in Atlanta, Ga., Jimmy Higgins, Edra Rice (neg) (Box 1)
  - Mattox and Mattox Coats of Arms copies (neg), Feb 10, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Douglas and Jimmy portraits (Print), 1955 (Box 1)
  - Douglas and Jimmy portraits (neg), 1955 (Box 1)
  - Mary & Douglas (3 years) portraits (neg), July 1951 (Box 1)
  - Mary Mattox (in fur coat) and Kat Horton (neg), about 1965 (Box 1)
  - John Mattox home, School auditorium, lunch room (neg), July 25, 1953 (Box 1)
  - Mr. and Mrs. John D. Mattox, Mrs. John J. Mattox at Chester Elliott's home in Atlanta, Ga. (neg) (Box 1)
  - Mary Mattox Portrait (neg) (Box 1)
  - Building Living Room - Interior and Exterior of new Front Room (neg), Feb 21, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Construction of Living Room (neg), March 1960 (Box 1)
  - Douglas Mattox - Small Child and Family (neg) (Box 1)
  - Douglas in Front of Tent in Yard (neg), circa 1951 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Mattox family pictures, Douglas as a baby (neg) (Box 1)
  - Douglas in Davy Crockett outfit (neg), Sept 27, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Douglas in Davy Crockett outfit (Print), Sept 27, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Mary, John, and Douglas Mattox Miscellaneous (neg) (Box 1)
  - Little Bill, Mary & Douglas at New Bern waterfront (neg), Nov 1955 (Box 1)
  - Douglas & Mary at C.V. Carnival night - NC State (neg), April 21, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Douglas Mattox, portrait in sport shirt, freshman at State (neg), Sept 1966 (Box 1)
  - Douglas Mattox in Cap & Gown (neg), June 1966 (Box 1)
  - Snow Scenes in Wendell, Douglas with Sled (neg), Jan 1955 (Box 1)
  - Mattox Family Portraits (John, Mary, & Douglas) (neg), July 14, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Mattox Family Portraits (John, Mary, & Douglas) (Print), July 14, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Mary's Bridge Club (neg), July 1951 (Box 1)
  - Mary's Kodak Film (miscellaneous group pictures, unidentified) (neg) (Box 1)
  - John Mattox in Little Theatre Production (Print) (Box 1)
  - John Mattox portraits (neg), 1962 (Box 1)
  - John Mattox portraits (Print), Feb 15, 1956 (Box 1)
  - John Mattox portraits (neg), Feb 15, 1956 (Box 1)
  - John Mattox (informal portrait) (neg), Summer 1958 (Box 1)
  - John Mattox portrait (neg), March 7, 1958 (Box 1)
  - John Mattox portrait (Print) (Box 1)
  - John Mattox portrait (neg), Jan 12, 1972 (Box 1)
  - John Mattox portrait (Print), Jan 12, 1972 (Box 1)
  - John Mattox portrait, in bow tie with dark background (neg), Aug 10, 1950 (Box 1)
  - John Mattox portrait, in bow tie with dark background (Print), Aug 10, 1950 (Box 1)
  - John Mattox portrait (Print), Nov 29, 1973 (Box 1)
  - John Mattox portrait (neg), Nov 29, 1973 (Box 1)
  - John Mattox portrait (Print), May 23, 1957 (Box 1)
  - John Mattox portrait (neg), May 23, 1957 (Box 1)
  - John Mattox portrait (neg), May 1960 (Box 1)
  - John Mattox, Freshman portrait (neg) (Box 1)
  - John Mattox baby & school pictures (neg) (Box 1)
  - John Mattox baby pictures (Print) (Box 1)
  - John Mattox, baby pictures (Print) (Box 5)
  - Wendell High School, John Mattox class & football team photos (Print), circa 1928 (Box 5)
  - Mary & Douglas Mattox portraits (neg), Feb 8, 1957 (Box 5)
  - John & Mary Mattox portraits (neg) (Box 5)
  - John Mattox and house (Print) (Box 5)
  - John Mattox Portraits (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Mary Mattox at Receptions (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - John Mattox, Atlanta (Glass Plate) (Box 9)
  - Mary Mattox, Atlanta (Glass Plate) (Box 9)
  - Doug Mattox Portrait (Flatfolder 10)
- Extended Family Photographs
  This series contains portraits and snapshots of John and Mary Mattox’s extended families, the including siblings, parents, aunts and uncles, and other relatives. John Mattox was the son of Jonathan Joseph and Ernestine Bain Mattox of Wendell, North Carolina. His siblings include Jeanette Mattox Laing, Annie Sue Mattox Faison, Vernon Mattox, and Edward Mattox. Family names in this series include Mattox, Davis, Bain, Faison, and Todd. Due to inconsistent labeling, it is possible that some of the photographs in this series depict individuals not actually related to Mattox.
  - Jeannette's Shower (neg), Aug 5, 1955 (Box 2)
  - Nan Mattox with Long Hair (neg), 1964 (Box 2)
  - Mr. Curt Todd (grandfather) from Sunday School group (neg) (Box 2)
  - Mamma portraits (Mattox's mother), Atlanta, Ga. (neg) (Box 2)
  - Mamma, Daddy portraits (Mattox's parents), made by Wilson Photography at Hotel Rigsbie(?) (Print), Aug 22, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Mamma, Daddy portraits (Mattox's parents), made by Wilson Photography at Hotel Rigsbie(?) (neg), Aug 22, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Davis Coat of Arms, ordered by Mary Mattox (neg), Dec 1974 (Box 2)
  - Mary Davis and brothers and sister, copy (neg) (Box 2)
  - Edna Davis, copy (Print) (Box 2)
  - Edna Davis, copy (neg) (Box 2)
  - Lee and Alma Mattox 50th Anniversary (Print), April 1976 (Box 2)
  - Lee and Alma Mattox 50th Anniversary (neg), April 1976 (Box 2)
  - Vernon Mattox Wedding (neg) (Box 2)
  - Hat House, Mammas (neg), Oct 13, 1951 (Box 2)
  - Vernon's Children (neg), Nov 25, 1962 (Box 2)
  - Mattox Family group at church, Mattox Family Christmas party (neg), 1952 (Box 2)
  - Thursday Afternoon Club, Mamma serving punch (neg), Oct 10, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Old Mattox graveyard near Saratoga, N.C. (neg), March 5, 1963 (Box 2)
  - Bain Reunion, Wendell Women's Club (neg), 1965 (Box 2)
  - Mattox uncles & Aunt Bertie; Robert, Lee, Ben, & Luther (neg), Christmas 1953 (Box 2)
  - Lawrence J. Davis (Mary's father), copy (neg), Nov 17, 1949 (Box 2)
  - Mary Mattox's father, portrait (Print) (Box 2)
  - Luther Mattox for Christian Church (neg), 1980 (Box 2)
  - Luther Mattox for Aunt Martha (neg), Dec 1979 (Box 2)
  - Aunt Berty, copy (Print) (Box 2)
  - Aunt Berty, copy (neg) (Box 2)
  - Great grandfather daguerreotype, copy (Print), May 1982 (Box 2)
  - Great grandfather daguerreotype, copy (neg), May 1982 (Box 2)
  - Mattox reunions at cousin Jim's (neg) (Box 2)
  - Mattox reunions at cousin Jim's (neg) (Box 2)
  - Mattox reunions at cousin Jim's (neg) (Box 2)
  - John Mattox's father with dog (neg) (Box 2)
  - Mattox family Christmas reunion Lion's club (neg), Dec 26, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Mattox family Christmas reunion Lion's club (Print), Dec 26, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Gus Faison with boy (neg) (Box 2)
  - Aunt Martha Todd Portrait (Print), March 9, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Aunt Martha Todd Portrait (neg), March 9, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Martha Todd Day, Wendell Christian Church (neg), Oct 5, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Jan & Azalea plant (grown by Dr. Roy A. Larson in greenhouse) (Print), Jan 25, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Jan & Azalea plant (neg), Jan 25, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Lee Mattox (neg), March 1970 (Box 2)
  - Aunt Martha, New Baptist, Jenny Knott (Print), Aug 1968 (Box 2)
  - Aunt Martha, New Baptist, Jenny Knott (neg), Aug 1968 (Box 2)
  - Aunt Martha church groups; Ki Rho group at Aunt Martha's (neg), Dec 1954 (Box 2)
  - Aunt Martha with New Organ at Home (neg) (Box 2)
  - Aunt Martha - Passport (Print), Feb 22, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Aunt Martha - Passport (neg), Feb 22, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Aunt Martha - Group (neg) (Box 2)
  - Aunt Martha Todd - Passport (Print), May 1, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Aunt Martha Todd - Passport (neg), May 1, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Aunt Martha - Young Girl (Print) (Box 2)
  - Aunt Martha - Young Girl (neg) (Box 2)
  - Aunt Martha - Passport (neg), Jan 31, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Unidentifided Party or Reception (neg), circa 1979 (Box 2)
  - Bruce Knott Portrait (neg), Aug 15, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Nellie Mattox - Passport Portrait for citizenship papers (neg), Aug 26, 1954 (Box 2)
  - Johnny Mattox Portrait, about one year (neg) (Box 2)
  - Curtis & Judy - Passports (Print), March 23, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Curtis & Judy - Passports (neg), March 23, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Nellie Mattox Portrait (neg), July 1966 (Box 2)
  - Alma Mattox Portrait (Print) (Box 2)
  - Alma Mattox Portrait (neg) (Box 2)
  - Laurie Grover Portrait (neg), Nov 1955 (Box 2)
  - Laurie Grover Portrait (Print), Nov 1955 (Box 2)
  - Portrait - Frances Ledford, High School Senior (Print), May 29, 1958 (Box 2)
  - Portrait - Frances Ledford, High School Senior (neg), May 29, 1958 (Box 2)
  - Nan Mattox, Basketball in Gym, Wendell, N.C. (neg) (Box 2)
  - Mary, Annie Sue, Edward, & Marion (neg), April 6, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Jim Higgins Portrait (Print), Feb 19, 1955 (Box 2)
  - Jim Higgins Portrait (neg), Feb 19, 1955 (Box 2)
  - Jim, Laury, & Babies (neg), Spring 1959 (Box 2)
  - Bonnie Sue Portrait (neg), Nov 27, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Lonnie Knott Passport Portrait (Print), Sept 30, 1958 (Box 2)
  - Lonnie Knott Passport Portrait (neg), Sept 30, 1958 (Box 2)
  - Pa Mattox (Print) (Box 2)
  - Pa Mattox (neg) (Box 2)
  - Uncle Mallie Todd (young man), copy (Print), 1980 (Box 2)
  - Uncle Mallie Todd (young man), copy (neg), 1980 (Box 2)
  - Benard Mattox (Gregory Walcott & wife) (Print), April 1959 (Box 2)
  - Benard Mattox (Gregory Walcott & wife) (neg), April 1959 (Box 2)
  - Ashley (16 months), John & Sandy Roberts (Print), March 7, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Ashley (16 months), John & Sandy Roberts (neg), March 7, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Portraits - Vernon, Nellie Mattox & Children (neg) (Box 2)
  - Edward Faison - with Mary, Doug, & Marion (neg), Feb 6, 1958 (Box 2)
  - Unidentified Wedding (Print), circa 1950s (Box 2)